Guide to the Vincent McHugh Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Vincent McHugh papers
1933-1983
YCAL MSS 631
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
58.93
(72 boxes)
The Vincent McHugh Papers document the professional and personal life of poet, novelist, and editor Vincent McHugh. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, professional papers, journals, notebooks, personal papers, photographs, sound recordings, drawings, and a scrapbook, spanning the years 1933 to 1983.
McHugh, Vincent, 1904-1983
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Serendipity Books on the The Bradford F. and Lila L. Swan Fund and Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2002; Gift of Patricia McHugh, 2003 and 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 68 (reel-to-reel audio tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 69 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Vincent McHugh (1904-1983)
Vincent McHugh was an American poet, novelist, and editor. He served as editor-in-chief and Technical Director of the New York office of the Federal Writers Project during the Depression, was a staff writer for The New Yorker in the late 1930's and was a writer-director for the Office of War Information Films. He published five novels, including The Victory (1947), I am Thinking of My Darling (1943), and Caleb Catlum's America (1936). His published poetry collections include Alpha: The Mutabilities (1958); The Blue Hen's Chickens, Poems, Verses, Blues (1947); and Old Friends from Far Away (1980), an English translation of classical Mandarin poems. He was married to Patricia McHugh and had no children.
Scope and Contents
The Vincent McHugh Papers document the professional and personal life of poet, novelist, and editor Vincent McHugh. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, professional papers, journals, notebooks, personal papers, photographs, sound recordings, drawings, and a scrapbook, spanning the years 1933 to 1983.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: I. March 2002 Acquisition, 1933-1983. II. October 2003 Acquisition, 1949-1978. III. July 2005 Acquisition, 1963.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Translators -- United States -- Archives; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Drawings (visual works); Photographs -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Translators -- United States -- 20th Century; McHugh, Vincent, 1904-1983
- March 2002 Acquisition, 1933-1983; 1; 58.3; (70 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This material is organized under eight headings: Correspondence, Writings, Professional Papers, Personal Papers, Journals and Notebooks, Photographs, and Sound Recordings.
  Correspondence contains personal and professional correspondence between Vincent McHugh and various individuals. Writings are autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of various writings, including McHugh's Alpha: The Mutabilities, The Victory, Primer of the Novel, Chinese poetry translations, poetry, reviews, as well as research material for writings on various topics, and other writings. Professional Papers contain lecture, course and teaching materials; and materials relating to McHugh's work with The Works Progress Administration, Office of War Information Films, Writer's War Board, Paramount Pictures, and other professional affiliations. Personal Papers include financial and travel material and other personal papers. Journals and Notebooks contain McHugh's personal journals and notebooks with writings and other notes. Photographs are snapshots of personal and professional subjects. Sound Recordings include various readings of McHugh's poetry and dictation of his autobiography.
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 247
  - Correspondence
    A list of correspondents provided by the vendor is filed in boxes 1, 4, 7, 11, 12, and 13.
    Correspondence is organized in four separate alphabetical runs, which have not been merged and organized as a whole.
    - "A" General, 1936-1957, undated; 4 (Box 1)
    - "B" General, 1936-1954, undated; 4 (Box 1)
    - "C" General, 1936-1958, undated; 5 (Box 1)
    - "D" General, 1946-1959, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - "E" General, 1937-1957, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - "F" General, 1937-1957, undated; 7 (Box 1)
    - "G" General, 1936-1952, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - "H" General, 1935-1959, undated; 5 (Box 1)
    - "I" General, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
    - "J" General, 1939-1959, undated (Box 2)
    - "K" General, 1947-1959; 5 (Box 2)
    - "L" General, 1943-1954, undated; 4 (Box 2)
    - "M" General, 1938-1957, undated; 17 (Box 2)
    - McCall, Monica, 1944-1958; 8 (Box 3)
    - "N" General, 1946-1956, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - "O" General, 194301952 (Box 3)
    - "P" General, 1936-1952, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - "R" General, 1940-1955; 5 (Box 3)
    - "S" General, 1938-1955, undated; 10 (Box 3)
    - "T" General, 1936-1954, undated (Box 3)
    - "U" General, 1946-1947 (Box 3)
    - "V" General, 1947, undated (Box 3)
    - "W" General, 1946-1956, undated (Box 3)
    - "Y" General, 1947-1956, undated (Box 3)
    - "A" General, 1962-1976, undated (Box 4)
    - Alsberg, Henry G., 1960-1969, undated (Box 4)
    - Authors Guild, Inc., 1903-1966 (Box 4)
    - "B" General, 1962-1982, undated (Box 4)
    - "C" General, 1962-1980, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Combs, Tram, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
    - "D" General, 1963-1982 (Box 4)
    - Ehrlich, Arnold, 1962-1969 (Box 4)
    - "F" General, 1962-1981 (Box 4)
    - "G" General, 1960-1977 (Box 4)
    - "H" General, 1960-1978, undated (Box 4)
    - "I" General, 1962-1969 (Box 4)
    - "J" General, 1963-1978 (Box 4)
    - "K" General, 1960-1980, undated (Box 4)
    - Kwock, C. H., 1965-1981, undated (Box 4)
    - "L" General, 1962-1978, undated (Box 4)
    - "M" General, 1962-1981, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - McCall, Monica, 1960-1968 (Box 4)
    - McHugh, Pat, 1967-1982, undated (Box 4)
    - McHugh, Leonard, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - Michaelson, Mike, 1963-1979, undated (Box 4)
    - "N" General, 1962-1980 (Box 4)
    - "O" General, 1960-1968, undated (Box 4)
    - "P" General, 1965-1971 (Box 4)
    - "R" General, 1960-1973 (Box 5)
    - "S" General, 1963-1975, undated (Box 5)
    - Sister Mary Dominic, 1966-1973; 2 (Box 5)
    - "T" General, 1962-1981, undated (Box 5)
    - Thompson, James H., 1962-1965 (Box 6)
    - "U" General, 1963, undated (Box 6)
    - "V" General, 1965-1973 (Box 6)
    - "W" General, 1960-1968 (Box 6)
    - Wong, Zeppelin W., 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - "A" General, 1962-1980 (Box 7)
    - "B" General, 1960-1978 (Box 7)
    - Botsford, Keith, 1967-1973 (Box 7)
    - "C" General, 1960-1980; 2 (Box 7)
    - "D" General, 1962-1981, undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - "E" General, 1962-1972, undated (Box 7)
    - "F" General, 1960-1980; 2 (Box 7)
    - "G" General, 1960-1981 (Box 7)
    - "H" General, 1960-1982, undated (Box 7)
    - "J" General, 1962-1980 (Box 7)
    - "K" General, 1965-1980 (Box 7)
    - Kwock, C. H., 1960-1980; 2 (Box 7)
    - Kwock, C. H., 1960-1980 (Box 8)
    - "L" General, 1960-1979; 2 (Box 8)
    - McCall, Monica, 1960-1977; 6 (Box 9)
    - "M" General, circa 1960-1980; 6 (Box 9)
    - McHugh, Vincent, outgoing correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 10)
    - "N" General, 1960-1978 (Box 10)
    - National Translation Center, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 10)
    - O'Neill, Helen H., 1976-1978 (Box 10)
    - "P" General, 1962-1971, undated (Box 10)
    - Quinn, Frank, 1962 July 19 (Box 10)
    - "R" General, 1962-1973 (Box 10)
    - "S" General, 1960-1981, undated; 6 (Box 10)
    - Sions, Harry, 1961-1971; 2 (Box 10)
    - "T" General, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
    - U. S. Treasury Department, undated (Box 10)
    - "V" General, 1965-1968 (Box 10)
    - "W" General, 1962-1982, undated; 3 (Box 10)
    - "Y" General, 1964-1968 (Box 10)
    - Ziminski, Adele, 1978 April (Box 10)
    - Unsorted, 1950-1981, undated; 10 (Box 11)
    - "A" General, 1946, undated (Box 12)
    - "B" General, 1964-1978 (Box 12)
    - Crowe, Peter, 1973-1978 (Box 12)
    - Davies, Valentine & Elizabeth, 1960 December 19 (Box 12)
    - Gibans, Nina & Jim, 1962 December 16 (Box 12)
    - Helm, Bob & Kay, 1960-1963 (Box 12)
    - Kurihara, Nanae, 1976 December 20 (Box 12)
    - "L" General, 1960-1977 (Box 12)
    - "M" General, 1960-1971 (Box 12)
    - Parenti, Tony, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - "S" General, 1971 December (Box 12)
    - "T" General, 1960-1973 (Box 12)
    - Wilde, John, 1963 December 31 (Box 12)
    - Unsorted, 1950s-1960s; 23 (Box 13)
    - Unsorted, 1950s-1960s; 8 (Box 14)
  - Writings
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 38 (Box 15)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 24 (Box 16)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 37 (Box 17)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 33 (Box 18)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 34 (Box 19)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 37 (Box 20)
    - Alpha: the Mutabilities, 1959-1972, undated; 12 (Box 21)
    - Chinese Poetry Translations
      - Night: I climb on the City Wall and Hear a Flute Playing, undated (Box 22)
      - Under the Moon: Drinking Alone, undated (Box 22)
      - To My Husband, undated (Box 22)
      - Winter Evening: Rejoicing at a Friend's Coming, undated (Box 22)
      - Looking at Spring, undated (Box 22)
      - Questions About a Bite, undated (Box 22)
      - Pity for the Farmer Conscripts, undated (Box 22)
      - On Not Seeing Li Po, undated (Box 22)
      - To My Younger Brother Ts-Yu, undated (Box 22)
      - Till White Hair We'll Stay Together, undated (Box 22)
      - Snow and Plum, undated (Box 22)
      - Spring Evening, undated (Box 22)
      - Sent to My Husband, undated (Box 22)
      - Chance Stroll, undated (Box 22)
      - Parting, undated (Box 22)
      - Message Someone Sent to a Loved Woman, undated (Box 22)
      - A Poem, undated (Box 22)
      - The Sad River, undated (Box 22)
      - To Tsu Erh Leaving Ch'i-Chou, undated (Box 22)
      - My House on Chung-Nah Mountain, undated (Box 22)
      - Climbing Crane Tower, undated (Box 22)
      - Reading the Ancient Classic Hills and Seas, undated (Box 22)
      - One Winter Night He Rejoices That a Friend Has Come to Visit, undated (Box 22)
      - Old Friend from Far Away, undated (Box 22)
      - Why I Live on the Mountain, undated (Box 22)
      - Lady and the Hermit, undated (Box 22)
      - Returning to Chiang Village, undated (Box 22)
      - Printed Material on Chinese from the Asia Society, undated (Box 22)
      - Have Pity on the Grass, undated (Box 22)
      - Talk: Classical Chinese Poetry, undated (Box 22)
      - Written to the Tune of Che-Ku T'ien, undated (Box 22)
      - Wu-Tung Shadows, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Tune of P'u-Sa Man, undated (Box 22)
      - Written to the Tune of Pu Suan Tzu, undated (Box 22)
      - Liang-Chou Song, undated (Box 22)
      - Farewell, undated (Box 22)
      - Listening to Rain: Written to the Tune of Yu Mei Jen, undated (Box 22)
      - Domestic Scene, undated (Box 22)
      - Ch'eng The Melody, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Tune of Chien Tzu Mu-Lan Hua, undated (Box 22)
      - Poem Written to an Old Tune, undated (Box 22)
      - Written to the Tune of Sheng Ch'a Tzu, undated (Box 22)
      - A Beauty, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Air of Yu Chia Ngao, undated (Box 22)
      - Air Nan Ko Tze, undated (Box 22)
      - Air Huan Ch'i Sa, undated (Box 22)
      - Yueh Chao Li- Hua, undated (Box 22)
      - Wang (Moral poems), undated (Box 22)
      - Grief at Being Parted, undated (Box 22)
      - Air Hao Shih Chin, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Air of P'u Sa Män, undated (Box 22)
      - Wang Fa-Ch'i's Poems, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Air of Yung Tao, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Air of Yu Mong Ling, undated (Box 22)
      - Have Pity on the Grass, undated (Box 22)
      - Empty envelope, undated (Box 22)
      - To the Air Lin Chiang Hsien, undated (Box 22)
      - Feng Huang, undated (Box 22)
    - The Victory, undated; 51 (Box 23)
    - Primer of the Novel, 1949 August 14, undated; 6 (Box 24)
    - Primer of the Novel, 1949 August 14, undated; 8 (Box 25)
    - Poetry drafts, undated; 55 (Box 26)
    - Poetry drafts, undated; 35 (Box 27)
    - The Unfortunate Traveler or, The Man Who Ate the Flag, undated; 7 (Box 28)
    - Gion Matsuri, undated; 15 (Box 28)
    - The Alone Men, 1950-1951, undated; 8 (Box 28)
    - Here We Go or, The Old Creation, undated; 17 (Box 29)
    - Poem, undated (Box 30)
    - The Journey Prayer, undated (Box 30)
    - Poems, undated; 4 (Box 30)
    - Ode after Ronsard, undated (Box 30)
    - No More Tonight, undated (Box 30)
    - Copybook Maxims, undated (Box 30)
    - Emotion Recollected in Tranquility, undated (Box 30)
    - And Leave the Driving to Us, undated (Box 30)
    - The Wild Duck, undated (Box 30)
    - Dos Passos and the Thirty Thousand Souls, undated (Box 30)
    - The Women of Lemnos, undated; 2 (Box 30)
    - Five Poems by Li Ch'ing Chao, undated (Box 30)
    - Six Poems by Wang-Fan-Chih, undated (Box 30)
    - The Mantis Friend, undated (Box 30)
    - Tenggara Laut, undated (Box 30)
    - Drinking Song, undated (Box 30)
    - Primer of the Novel - Excerpts, undated (Box 30)
    - Sea of Nusantara, undated (Box 30)
    - The Sworn Son, undated (Box 30)
    - Contemporary Literature, undated (Box 30)
    - The Women of Reno, undated (Box 30)
    - Death and the Maidens, undated (Box 30)
    - The Biggest Alarm Clock in the World, undated (Box 30)
    - The Rusty Lilac, undated (Box 30)
    - How Come Chrysanthemum?, undated (Box 30)
    - Rainy Sunday in San Francisco, undated (Box 30)
    - Homage to the 'New Critics': Now, Alas, Old, undated (Box 30)
    - Inscription on a Stone at Cape Forlon, undated (Box 30)
    - The Natural History of Pliny, undated (Box 30)
    - The Case on the Human Race, undated (Box 30)
    - Note on the Back of an Envelope, undated (Box 30)
    - The Beggar Laddie, undated (Box 30)
    - Bahian Song, undated (Box 30)
    - The Great Elopement, undated (Box 30)
    - Duessa, undated (Box 30)
    - Unsorted manuscript notes, undated (Box 30)
    - Hagia Poetry, undated; 13 (Box 30)
    - Unsorted manuscript notes, undated; 3 (Box 30)
    - Unsorted manuscript notes, undated; 3 (Box 31)
    - Gion Matsuri, undated (Box 31)
    - The Women of Lemnos, undated; 5 (Box 31)
    - Passage to Spain, undated (Box 31)
    - The Hill Walkers, undated (Box 31)
    - Her by Lawrence Ferlinghetti, review, undated (Box 31)
    - Ida and the Black Lace Nightgown, undated (Box 31)
    - The Case on the Human Race, undated (Box 31)
    - A Word from the Gate, undated (Box 31)
    - Flowers for Jake, undated (Box 31)
    - Mama Cat's Blues, undated (Box 31)
    - The Women of Lemnos, undated (Box 31)
    - Death and the Maidens, undated (Box 31)
    - Love Letter to Block Island, undated (Box 31)
    - The Biggest Alarm Clock, undated (Box 31)
    - Darwin for Orders, undated (Box 31)
    - Odd Man In, circa 1965 (Box 31)
    - Untitled, 1942 February 12 (Box 31)
    - Archilochos, undated; 2 (Box 32)
    - Gion Matsuri, undated; 2 (Box 32)
    - Summer is a Country, 1940 (Box 32)
    - The Sociable Arts, 1938 (Box 32)
    - Little Big Horn and the Gardenia, 1940 (Box 32)
    - The Shadow Knows, 1940 (Box 32)
    - Descent on the City, 1933 (Box 32)
    - The Orphan, undated (Box 32)
    - The Rusty Lilac, undated (Box 32)
    - The Man Who Wanted Quiet, undated (Box 32)
    - The Dream and the Deal, review, undated (Box 32)
    - The Blues for Jimmy, undated (Box 32)
    - Splice the Main Brace, undated (Box 32)
    - The Man Who Ate the Flag, 1939, undated (Box 32)
    - Article suggestions, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 32)
    - San Diego Zoo, undated; 3 (Box 32)
    - San Diego Zoo, undated; 3 (Box 33)
    - Block Island materials, 1951-1952, undated; 2 (Box 33)
    - Twenty Cities, 1980-1981; 5 (Box 33)
    - Bangkok, undated; 5 (Box 33)
    - A New Diaspora, undated (Box 33)
    - No Banners in the Street, 1948 (Box 33)
    - Purisma, 1966, undated; 7 (Box 33)
    - Novel No. 4, undated; 4 (Box 33)
    - Unsorted manuscripts and notes, 1939-1983, undated; 23 (Box 34)
    - The Picture Man, 1960 November 20, undated (Box 34)
    - Republican National Convention material, 1966 July; 2 (Box 34)
    - Gung Hay, 1955, undated; 5 (Box 34)
    - The Women of Lemnos, undated; 6 (Box 35)
    - Notes from an obscenity trial, 1947 May-June (Box 35)
    - The Lady and the Hermit, undated (Box 35)
    - Treasury of the Pacific, undated; 2 (Box 35)
    - The Diajin, undated (Box 35)
    - Babies and Publishers, or Finocchio's on My Night Out, undated (Box 35)
    - Saturday Night Band Wagon, undated (Box 35)
    - KPFA notes, undated (Box 35)
    - Look Behind You, 1938; 2 (Box 35)
    - San Francisco Films Memorandum, 1955 (Box 35)
    - Gung Hay, undated (Box 35)
    - Golden Gate Bridge, undated (Box 35)
    - Narration: On Stream Anacortes, undated (Box 35)
    - Gadabout, undated (Box 35)
    - Articles about Newport, Rhode Island, circa 1947; 7 (Box 35)
    - Mrs. Angell, undated; 14 (Box 35)
    - Denver's the Place To Be in Summer, 1969; 4 (Box 36)
    - Thoughts of Chairman Wen Chang, 1971, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - Poetry in the Birdhouse, undated (Box 36)
    - Old Antonio, undated (Box 36)
    - The Snow Maidens, undated (Box 36)
    - The Money Doctor, undated (Box 36)
    - Potpourri, undated (Box 36)
    - Bete Noire in Sainte-Beuye, undated (Box 36)
    - The Mysterious Umbrella, undated (Box 36)
    - How the Bad Times Come, undated (Box 36)
    - The Rivers of Venice, undated (Box 36)
    - The Blue Hen's Chickens, undated (Box 36)
    - The Rusty Lilac, undated (Box 36)
    - The Long Watch, undated (Box 36)
    - The Nine Lives of California, undated; 3 (Box 36)
    - Daylight Star, undated (Box 36)
    - Conrad's Victory, undated (Box 36)
    - Moon Festival: The Basic Legend, undated (Box 36)
    - Financing Nancy, undated (Box 36)
    - All God's Chillun Got a Horn, undated (Box 36)
    - Land of Goshen, undated (Box 36)
    - Sweet Bells, undated (Box 36)
    - Chronicle, undated; 8 (Box 36)
    - Darwin for Orders, undated (Box 36)
    - Uncle John's Balliwick, undated (Box 36)
    - The Symbolist Aesthetic in France, undated (Box 36)
    - Forty-Plus, undated (Box 36)
    - The Lieutenant Governor's Eyes, undated (Box 36)
    - I Felt a Funeral in My Brain, undated (Box 36)
    - The Case of the Human Race, 1949 (Box 36)
    - Monterey, undated (Box 36)
    - Hiroshima - 1965 - The Dark City, undated (Box 36)
    - Suzy's Matisse, undated (Box 36)
    - New View of Japan, undated (Box 36)
    - Revolt of the Slaveys, undated (Box 36)
    - Reviews, undated; 4 (Box 36)
    - Tenggara Laut, undated; 2 (Box 37)
    - The Trap, undated (Box 37)
    - A Crowd of Ships, undated (Box 37)
    - The Wild Duck, undated (Box 37)
    - The Women of Reno, undated (Box 37)
    - The Admiral's Badge, undated (Box 37)
    - Books, 1942 October 12 (Box 37)
    - Annawamscutt, 1942 (Box 37)
    - The Wind that Shakes the Barley, 1942 (Box 37)
    - City Called Heaven, 1942 (Box 37)
    - Open Country, undated; 4 (Box 37)
    - The Celebes Story, 1952, undated; 7 (Box 37)
    - Edge of the World, undated; 7 (Box 37)
    - Meaningless Day, undated (Box 38)
    - Water Man, undated (Box 38)
    - DGE Bulletin: The Freeing of Living Things, undated (Box 38)
    - The Green Man, undated (Box 38)
    - The Figure of a Woman, undated; 3 (Box 38)
    - Triple Lap Dissolve, undated (Box 38)
    - The Picture Man, undated (Box 38)
    - The Passage, undated (Box 38)
    - Joe Below, undated (Box 38)
    - Review of Gate of Hell, undated (Box 38)
    - Governor's Mansion Piece, 1962-1967; 4 (Box 38)
    - Turbulence in the Third Hour, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - The Ghouls, undated (Box 38)
    - Where the Bones Go, undated (Box 38)
    - They Couldn't Be Bothered, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - Earthquake and fire notes, undated (Box 38)
    - Sloughs, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - The Bridge at Howrah, undated (Box 38)
    - How to Fake a Shower, undated (Box 38)
    - It Huffed and It Puffed, undated (Box 38)
    - The Bride was Dressed in White, undated (Box 38)
    - The Wooing of Cowtail Belle, undated (Box 38)
    - Old Friend from Far Away, undated (Box 38)
    - The Hill Walkers, undated (Box 38)
    - The Tourist, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - Water Country, undated; 4 (Box 38)
    - Press Kits, 1968-1969, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - Time of Love, undated; 4 (Box 39)
    - Lover of Legends, Witness and Wanting, Comforter of the Afflicted, Lecturer to the Law, Abysmal Brute, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - Marion, daughter of Milton and Annie..., undated (Box 39)
    - Unsorted poems, undated (Box 39)
    - Comments on other people's pieces, undated (Box 39)
    - New York Rock & Roll Ensemble, undated (Box 39)
    - Jimmy John Fair by Ray Davidson, undated; 13 (Box 39)
    - Angel-Face Blakeleigh by Julius G. Rothenberg, undated (Box 39)
    - Trouble in the Air by Kenneth Kay, undated (Box 39)
    - Rambo and the Rats by Lt. Col. Ken E. Kay, undated (Box 39)
    - 30: A Play by Tim J. Sullivan, undated (Box 39)
    - A Prayer for the Dead by Tim J. Sullivan, undated (Box 40)
    - The Apprenticeship of David Bruner by Abraham Morganstern, 1942 November 2; 3 (Box 40)
    - Contracts and correspondence, 1944-1958; 4 (Box 41)
    - Gaijin, 1968, undated; 2 (Box 41)
    - Jimmy Marshall material, undated (Box 41)
    - Comments, 1938; 2 (Box 41)
    - Production # 128: Flat-Top, 1943 April 4 (Box 41)
    - The Gaijin, undated (Box 41)
    - Various writing drafts, undated (Box 41)
    - Picture Man, undated (Box 41)
    - The Women of Lemnos, undated (Box 41)
    - Translation proposals, 1968 September 16 (Box 41)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 41)
    - National Translation Center, 1967-1968; 2 (Box 41)
    - Various writing drafts, 1936-1948, undated; 16 (Box 41)
    - Unsorted notes, circa 1948-1968, undated; 11 (Box 42)
    - Unsorted notes, circa 1948-1968, undated; 9 (Box 43)
    - California Parks Piece: manuscripts, printed material and notes, 1950-1964, undated; 33 (Box 44)
    - California Parks Piece: manuscripts, printed material and notes, 1950-1964, undated; 10 (Box 45)
    - Fishing and Hunting newspaper clippings, 1961-1963, undated (Box 46)
    - The Nereids, 1959 February 23 (Box 46)
    - Why I Live on the Mountain, undated (Box 46)
    - To a Yu-Men Friend, undated (Box 46)
    - The Lady and the Hermit, undated (Box 46)
    - MADS III, 1957 August 17, undated (Box 46)
    - Li and Wang, undated (Box 46)
    - Water, newspaper clippings, 1963 (Box 46)
    - California Farmer, Vol. 211, No. 5, 1959 August 29 (Box 46)
    - Printed material, 1951 (Box 46)
    - Life and Love of the Beaver, undated (Box 46)
    - DGE Bulletin, undated (Box 46)
    - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 46)
    - Printed material related to oil and gas in California, 1960-1962 (Box 46)
    - Port of Stockton, 1961 November 13, undated (Box 46)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1961-1964 (Box 46)
    - California State Fair and Exposition, 1963 (Box 46)
    - University of California, 1962 February 15 (Box 46)
    - The Phoenix on the Shield, undated (Box 46)
    - Columbia, 1964 April (Box 46)
    - Notebooks, 1962 February 13, undated (Box 46)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1963 (Box 46)
    - Third Pattern in Chinatown, undated (Box 46)